I'm Lizz, the creator of PO' UP!
Card Game,
which are party games celebrating black experiences
from college to the workplace.
I've been an Amazon Seller for a couple of years,
and today I'm going to share a few tips
for optimizing your listing on Amazon.
First things first, you want to make sure
that you have high quality product photos
ready to go for your listing.
And this should include a mix of product photos,
which are images of your product against a white backdrop
at different angles.
And this should also include a list of lifestyle photos,
which are images of people interacting with your product,
or images of your product in a usual setting
where people can find your product.
So for example, my card game is a party game.
So my lifestyle images include people
around a table playing the card game.
And I also have some images,
including the dimensions of the product,
and a few tips and ideas for where this product can be used.
What I also recommend for listing optimization
is looking at two to three competitor listings on Amazon,
copying their listings into an AI tool,
and asking this AI tool to help you develop
your own listing using keywords for SEO optimization.
And then what you're going to do
is you're going to copy the words
in that listing into your AI tool from your competitors.
From there, you're going to ask your AI tool
to create a listing for your product,
leveraging some of the key phrases and tips
used in your competitors listing
that should be leveraged in your own listing.
And don't forget to ask your AI tool
to make sure that your listing is optimized for SEO,
meaning that people are able to leverage keywords
to find your product on Amazon
when they're looking for maybe similar products
or looking for products in that category.
You want to make sure that your listing pops up,
and this is a great way to not have to develop
your listing from scratch
and to make sure that you are standing out
amongst your competitors.
And last but not least for listing optimization,
I recommend leveraging your A+ content on Amazon.
A+ content is what you see when you scroll
to the bottom of the listing
that provides more dynamic images explaining a product
in a way that you may not have been able to explain
at the top of a page, which is limited
to a certain number of words or characters.
Definitely take advantage of the A+ content,
add videos to your page where possible,
and just really make sure that your brand messaging,
but also your brand look and feel,
comes across by the time people scroll
to that portion of your listing.
I hope you found these tips helpful
for listing optimization on Amazon.